<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>读书笔记 on Xinlu&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>/categories/%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 读书笔记 on Xinlu&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>《Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind》读书笔记</title>
      <link>/20150702/sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20150702/sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/</guid>
      <description>The state and the market approached people with an offer that could not be refused. &amp;lsquo;Become individuals,&amp;rsquo; they said. &amp;lsquo;Marry whomever you desire, without asking permission from your parents. Take up whatever job suits you, even if community elders frown. Live wherever you wish, even if you cannot make it every week to the family dinner. You are no longer dependent on your family or your community. We, the state and the market, will take care of you instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>读刘未鹏的《暗时间》</title>
      <link>/20150112/%E8%AF%BB%E5%88%98%E6%9C%AA%E9%B9%8F%E7%9A%84%E6%9A%97%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20150112/%E8%AF%BB%E5%88%98%E6%9C%AA%E9%B9%8F%E7%9A%84%E6%9A%97%E6%97%B6%E9%97%B4/</guid>
      <description>最近读刘未鹏的《暗时间》有些感触。刘未鹏在书中将人的大脑比作CPU，对时间安排，处理任务等进行了一些阐述。我总结了一下：
How to use your time more efficiently  Time is one dimension, and intensity is the other&amp;ndash;The output is equal to Time X Intensity.   运行空闲进程也是一天，运行大数据量计算的程序也是一天，对于CPU来说同样的一天，价值却是完全不一样的。善于利用思维时间的人，可以无形中比别人多出很多时间
  Stop multitasking.   任务切换需要耗费许多额外的花销，通俗地来讲，首先需要保存当前上下文以便下次能够顺利切换回来，然后要加载目标任务的上下文。如果一个系统不停地在多个任务之间来回倒腾，就会耗费大量的时间在上下文切换上，无形中浪费很多的时间。
大脑开始一件任务的时候必须要有一定时间来“热身”，这个时间因人而异，并且可以通过练习来改变。
 For example. you can concentrate on researh during the working days, and leave other unimportant stuffs to the weekend. By doing so, you can reduce the switching cost, thus improving the efficency of your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《平凡的世界》读书笔记</title>
      <link>/20141230/%E5%B9%B3%E5%87%A1%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20141230/%E5%B9%B3%E5%87%A1%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%96%E7%95%8C%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/</guid>
      <description>“有文化的城里人，往往不能想象农村姑娘的爱情生活。在他们看来，也许没有文化就等于没有头脑；没有头脑就不懂得多少感情。可是实际也许和这种偏见恰恰相反。真的，正由于她们知识不多，精神不会太分散，对于两性之间的感情非常专注，所以这种感情实际上更丰富，更强烈。”
“尤其象田润叶这样的人，她尽管在县城参加了工作，但本质上也可以说仍然是一个农村姑娘。一旦当她第一次对一个男人产生了热烈的爱情，就会深陷进去而不能自拔。可一旦这热烈的向往落空，又很难从因此而造成的痛苦中解脱出来。她除过日常的生活和工作，又没有远大的事业上的追求来弥补感情上的损失……”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>